

Profil

I'm a web developer specializing in the **JavaScript** programming language and have extended my skills with **TypeScript**. I have a lot of experience as a **Microsoft** developer, so I have in-depth knowledge of **React**, **SharePoint**, **Azure** and **Microsoft Teams**. I know how to use **PowerShell** to automate and manage these technologies. My skills enable me to design and develop powerful, integrated web applications, specifically tailored to the needs and integrations required.

Professional Experience

Web Developer M365, Netmedia, Saarbrücken

FEBRUARY 2022 - SEPTEMBER 2023

Web application developer mastering React, TypeScript, SharePoint, Microsoft Teams, Microsoft Graph and PowerShell for efficient, collaborative solutions using agile methods.

JavaScript Fullstack Developer, FindQuickly, Sarreguemines

SEPTEMBER 2021 - JANUARY 2022

Full-stack JavaScript developer proficient in React, Node.js and Express. Expertise in building scalable web applications with a focus on delivering high-quality solutions.

Metalworker, Hans Leffer GmbH, Saarbrücken

AUGUST 2011 - JULY 2020

Military, Armée de terre, Sarrebourg

DECEMBER 2008 - NOVEMBER 2011

Education

Web developer internship, FindQuickly, Sarreguemines

FEBRUARY 2021 - AUGUST 2021

Learning fullstack development in JavaScript and TypeScript, I got to know MySQL and MongoDB databases.

Bachelor's degree, Esecad, Montrouge

SEPTEMBER 2020 - SEPTEMBER 2021

Web development training, learning HTML, CSS, PHP, MySQL, JavaScript and SEO. Mastering the creation of interactive interfaces, dynamic databases and optimizations for an exceptional online experience.

Self-training

JANUARY 2018 - PRESENT

Web application developer.

A-level commerce, Lycée Simon Lazard, Sarreguemines

SEPTEMBER 2005 - JULY 2008

Details

Puttelange-aux-Lacs, France + 33 6 45 92 26 14 hp.hectorpascal@gmail.com

Links

My portfolio

LinkedIn

CodeSandBox

<u>CodePen</u>

<u>GitHub</u>

Skills

JavaScript

TypeScript

React

Redux

Node

API REST

MySQL

MongoDB

Sass

Tailwind CSS

Material UI

Git

GitHub

Languages

French

German

English

Hobbies

Diving Programming Hiking